So, the idea for building our LDA model will be to factor are
构建这个 LDA 模型的原理是
Bag of Words matrix on the left into two matrices,
将左侧的词袋矩阵分解成两个矩阵
one indexing documents by topic and the other indexing topics by word.
一个的索引是文档和主题 另一个是主题和单词
In this video, I'll be more specific about what these matrices mean.
在此视频中 我将详细讲解这些矩阵的含义
Here's how we calculate our Bag of Words matrix.
计算词袋矩阵的方式如下
Let's say we have a document,
假设有一个文档 即文档 2
Document two which has the words space three times,
其中包含 space 3 次
climate and rule once each and no other words.
climate 和 rule 各 1 次 没有其他单词了
Remember that we process this document and
注意 我们处理了该文档
extracted the important words so things like is,
并提取出重要单词 使结果变成这样
the, and are not counted.
is 和 the 等单词不考虑
We write these numbers in the corresponding row.
将这些数字写在相应的行中
Now to find the probabilities,
要计算概率
we just divide by the row sum and we get three-fifths,
直接除以行的条目之和 结果为 3/5
one-fifth, one-fifth, and zeros for the rest.
1/5 1/5 剩下的为 0
That's our Bag of Words matrix.
这就是词袋矩阵
Our document topic matrix is as follows;
现在计算文档主题矩阵
Let's say we have a document say Document three,
假设有一个文档 3
and let's say we have a way to figure out that Document three is
我们能够判断文档 3
mostly about science and a bit about sports and politics.
主要讲的是科学 并且涉及了一些体育和政治
Let's say it's 70 percent about science,
假设 70% 关于科学
10 percent about politics,
10% 关于政治
and 20 percent about sports.
20% 关于体育
So, we just record these numbers in
将这些数字记录在相应的行中
the corresponding row and that's how we obtain this matrix.
得出了这个矩阵
The topic term matrix is similar.
主题术语矩阵也相似
Here we have a topic, say politics,
这里有一个主题是政治
and let's say we can figure out the probabilities that words are generated by this topic.
假设我们能够得出这个主题生成一些单词的概率
We take all this probabilities we should add to
这些概率之和应该为 1
one and put them in the corresponding row.
将它们放入相应的行
As we saw, the product of these two matrices is the Bag of Word matrix.
可以看出 这两个矩阵的积是词袋矩阵
Well, this is not exact but the idea is to get really close.
并不是要完全相等 而是要非常接近
If we can find two matrices whose product is very close to the Bag of Word matrix,
如果我们能够找到积非常接近词袋矩阵的两个矩阵
then we've created a topic model.
则创建了主题模型
But I still haven't told you how to calculate the entries in these two matrices.
但是我依然没有介绍如何计算这两个矩阵中的条目
Well, one way is using the traditional matrix factorization algorithm.
一种方法是使用传统的矩阵分解算法
This is out of the context of this course but in the instructor comments,
这已经超出了这门课程的范畴 我们在讲师备注中
we'll add some resources and keys you want to learn it more in detail.
给出了一些资源和提示 可以帮助你了解更多信息
However, these matrices are very special.
但是 这些矩阵非常特殊
For ones, the rows add up to one.
首先 行的和是 1
Also if you think about it,
并且仔细思考会发现
there's a lot of structure coming from a set of documents, topics and words.
一组文档 主题和单词存在很多结构
So, what we'll do is something a bit more elaborate than matrix multiplication.
我们采取的做法比矩阵乘法更复杂
The basic idea is the following: the entries in
基本原理是
the two topic modeling matrices come from some special distributions.
两个主题建模矩阵的条目来自特殊的分布图
So, we'll embrace this fact and work with these distributions to find these two matrices.
我们将根据这一事实利用这些分布得出这两个矩阵
We'll see this in the next few videos.
具体细节将在下面的几个视频中讲解